

# Marcel Scognamiglio

Date of birth: 10/08/1990

Nationality: Brazilian

**Gender:** Male

## CONTACT

Rua Mar Del Plata, Casa 12235340 São José dos Campos, Brazil

marcelx@protonmail.com

(+55) 11973913474

https://marcelxv.github.io/ portfolio

LinkedIn: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/marcel-lourenco/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/marcel-lourenco/</a>

**Whatsapp Messenger:** +5511 973913474



#### **ABOUT ME**

I am a front end developer and I have worked in agile environments, managed and participated in multidisciplinary teams with devs, copywriters and designers in order to deliver web applications. I use some of the most important web technologies to develop: frameworks and libraries like React and Wordpress; languages such as HTML, CSS3, Javascript; platforms like Woocommerce, Shopify, Webflow; methodologies such as UX Design, GIT, CI/CD and Agile. Today I'm looking for a position as Front End in a company that develops complex web applications; I seek to grow in software engineer.

I have 8 years of experience in which I worked as a freelancer and, more recently, as a leader in the development studio of which I am a partner, always being responsible for the delivery, maintenance and evolution of digital products such as websites, virtual stores, rich applications, blogs and content for startups such as Livraria Combo and Infinity Copy, stores for small local and multinational businesses such as Grand Hyatt Hotel, enabling my clients to increase revenue, optimize costs, facilitate the end user, reduce processes and brand exposure.

Experienced in dealing with stakeholders and in a variety of industries, I have developed a keen customer empathy and broad view of all aspects of building solutions for digital products, as well as an understanding of creating rich and scalable systems I am proactive and open to collaboration and willing to grow in the area.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

28/02/2019 - CURRENT - São José dos Campos, Brazil

## Web engineer

Agência NÓS

I attended, improved and developed digital products for more than 10 companies using technologies such as Wordpress, React, Shopify, Webflow, Javascript among others, generating more than R\$ 1 million in sales and 4 million unique visits.

I implemented the agile methodology in my process and my team improving the productivity in deliveries by 50%.

**04/03/2015 - 03/03/2019** - São Paulo, Brazil

## Web developers

Freelancing

I developed virtual stores and websites in HTML, CSS, and Wordpress for small businesses, NGOs and startups, facilitating more than 100,000 visits and more than BRL 10,000 in profits on the websites created for my clients.

01/03/2016 - 03/02/2017 - São Paulo, Brazil

#### Creative director

LS Comunicação

I created design pieces, websites, animations and apps for more than 5 clients in different areas such as culture, finance, politics and health.

#### **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

01/02/2009 - 03/11/2013

## **Communicator / Journalist**

**FAPCOM** 

fapcom.com.br

**03/08/2021 - CURRENT** - São Paulo, Brazil

**Systems for Internet Specialist** 

FIAP

fiap.com.br

### LANGUAGE SKILLS

MOTHER TONGUE(S): Portuguese

**OTHER LANGUAGE(S):** 

**English** 

<b>Listening</b> B2	<b>Reading</b> C2	Spoken production B2	Spoken interaction B2	<b>Writing</b> B2
Spanish Listening B1	<b>Reading</b> B1	Spoken production B1	Spoken interaction B1	<b>Writing</b> A2

## **DIGITAL SKILLS**

## Frameworks / Libraries

Shopify / Git / JQuery / HTML5 / Bootstrap / webflow / Liquid.js / Wordpress / React ecosystem: ReactJS, React Router, Redux, Typescript

## **Technologies**

Agile (Scrum) / Web Development / UX / Github / Object-Oriented Programming / JSON / MySQL / CSS / HTML / CSS3 / JavaScript

#### COMMUNICATION AND INTERPERSONAL SKILLS

## Empathy

Experienced in dealing with stakeholders and in various industries, I have developed a keen empathy with the customer and a broad view of all aspects of building solutions for digital products

## Problem-solving

I delivery more than 100 web apps to real clients: e-commerces, systems, templates, themes, pages, plugins and apps. Therefore I'd not touched and delivered all the code, all the time, in all the cases I was the person who identifies, builds and solves a problem with code.

## Supporting developers

I very communicative – I also have a communication degree, I create content in my LinkedIn and blog, tutoriais in my YouTube Channel but mostly important I love to answer my colleagues in university or in chat app in order to teach and guide them with my experiencies and learnings. I really believe and live by LEARN IN PUBLIC.

## Seeing big picture

I got almost 10 year of experience in digital product development and I'd occupy almost every role of it guide by PASSION to create new digital experiences: I was Web Designer, Product Owner, Scrum Master, front and back end developer (full stack), Manager (Webmaster), but always learning something to improve my frontend skills – to amplify my vision of the industry and my work. Aside to that fact, I worked in update of systems, that helps me to improve my understanding of use of must-be and might-be, excellence and goodenough.

#### Restless learner

I started my career as software developer by learning fast self taught how to program in HTML, CSS and PHP and the foundations of programming, logic and syntaxes. After, I learned JS, and then how to use frameworks and libraries as React, TypeScript and SCRUM. I'd never stopped learning and never will. More than understand its importance, I love to learn! And learn quickly.

Now I'm figuring out more about Machine Learning, as one of the first Brazilians developers that was invited to use GPT-3 via API.

#### **CREATIVE WORKS**

#### **2021 - CURRENT**

#### **Lo-fi Business**

An online community of web creators that uses or don't uses code to create stuff!

https://lofibusiness.com/

#### HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

## Music Production

https://music.youtube.com/channel/UCxP8DrLC6CbBco97nvOJjPQ

#### HONOURS AND AWARDS

10/10/2021

FIAP ENTERPRISE CHALLENGE 2021 #1 PLACE - FIAP

08/2021

FIAP ENTERPRISE CHALLENGE 2021 #2 PLACE - FIAP

## **PROJECTS**

#### **2020 - CURRENT**

## Editora Antofagica – Web Consultancy

I improved a book e-commerce from publisher Antofágica, highlighting: a) performance improvement – according to GTMetrix, there was an 80% improvement in loading time, b) infrastructure improvement when applying CDN and migration to a dedicated cloud environment, c) implementation of PIX (Brazil's new digital payment method) which appears as the main payment method of the publisher currently ed) creating a solid web project (UI Design in Figma) of components following the best practices for reuse, cohesion with the brand and usability. In addition, I trained the team that would operate the site's CMS and closely followed their needs by creating video tutorials whenever there was a need for additional training.

2020 - 2021

## Chief Buddha Officer - Web Developer

#### cbo.digita

I created a complete learning platform (LMS) to offer (paid) courses with a payment gateway, a student / course management system, which marked the beginning of the startup and made it possible for it to invoice, therefore with a 100% billing from the launch.

2019 - 2021

#### Combo - CTO

#### https://youtu.be/yvgna4tdXNU

I created a unique book e-commerce in product filtering (combining technologies and plugins), user experience (UX) inaugurating the online presence of the bookstore already consolidated in the physical world, transporting the consumer experience to the web environment and automating, in the backend via API, more than 10 processes with partners between book distributors, ERPs and payment methods. Combo was the first online bookstore in Brazil to offer payments via PIX, just 24 days after the launch of the payment method in Brazil.

#### 2019

## **Grand Hyatt Hotel - Training Plataform**

I created a complete platform for video training new employees of the hotel chain, with management of courses, users, content. The solution was responsible for saving training costs that were formerly carried out in person.